记得回到本节的开头
remember way back at the beginning of this section
我们向您介绍了质押控制器
we introduced you to a pledge controller
好吧，它现在应该可以工作了
well it should now work
因为我们已经实现了 create
because we've implemented create
承诺和最近的承诺
pledge and recent pledges
所以我重新启动了它
so I've restarted it
只是为了在这里得到一个完全干净的石板
just to get a totally clean slate here
我们将从
and we're going to start by
启动我们的质押服务器
firing up our pledge server
我们将使用我们方便的启动功能
we'll use our handy start function
好的，这会产生一个过程
all right and that gets spawned into a process
已处理一六十五
it's processed one sixty five
然后我们需要启动我们的http服务器
and then we need to start up our http server
我会像往常一样从 4000 端口开始
I'll start on port 4000 as usual
现在当我们在这里调用开始时
now when we call start here
这不会产生一个进程
this doesn't spawn a process
请记住，它只是为每个请求生成进程
remember it just spawns processes for each request
所以这会束缚性，但没关系
so this is going to tie up sex but that's okay
现在在一个单独的终端选项卡中
now over in a separate terminal tab
我们将使用 curl 发送一些请求
we'll use curl to send some requests
所以我们要发送的第一个请求
so the first request we're going to send to
削减承诺
slash pledges
这将是一个 git 请求
it's going to be a git request
所以这将兑现我们最近的承诺
so this is going to return our recent pledges
现在它只是一个空列表
and right now it's just an empty list
好吧，让我们创建一些承诺
all right so let's create some pledges
我要再次使用 curl
I'm going to use curl again
我将使用 x post 选项
I'm going to use the x post option
将此数据作为发布请求发布
to post this data as a post request
削减承诺
to slash pledges
这将由 crate 动作处理
and that's going to get handled by the crate action
我们的质押控制器
of our pledge controller
太阳能将承诺 100 美元
solar is going to pledge $100
然后我们将承诺 200 美元
and then we'll have mo pledged $200
curly会承诺300
curly's gonna pledge 300
黛西一旦参加了她会给我们400的行动
daisy once in on the action she's gonna give us 400
但不甘示弱
but not to be outdone as grace and
她给了我们五个
she's giving us five
我们可能会得到一两条鳄鱼
and we might just get ourselves an alligator or two
酷现在让我们看看我们最近的承诺
cool now let's have a look at our recent pledges
我们有我们最近的三个承诺
and we've got our three most recent pledges
回顾我们的质押服务器模块
looking back at our pledge server module
我们现在有五个
we now have five
这一模块中的功能
functions in this one module
重要的是要注意这些函数运行在
and it's important to note that these functions run in
不同的过程
different processes
这个启动函数被调用
this start function is called
由客户端生成服务器进程
by the client to spawn the server process
然后这个创建
then this create
这里的承诺和最近的承诺功能是
pledge and recent pledges functions down here are
也被客户端调用
also called by the client
它们在客户端进程中运行
and they run in the client process
所以让我们真正抓住那些
so let's actually grab those
我们会将所有客户端功能一起移动
and we'll move all the client functions together
我会像这样把这些放在开始
I'll put these up under start just like that
然后让我们在这里添加评论
and then let's add a comment up here
所有这些都是客户端接口功能
all of these are client interface functions
现在这里的监听循环不同了
now this listen loop down here is different
它被 spawn 调用
it's called by spawn
这意味着它在这个生成服务器进程中运行
which means it runs in this spawn server process
所以让我们在这里添加评论
so let's add a comment up here
下面的所有内容都在服务器中运行
everything below here is run in the server
首先
at first
单个模块可以有可能看起来很奇怪
it might seem strange that a single module can have
在不同的进程中运行不同的功能
different functions running in different processes
并且真的
and in really
您可能想要分开的复杂案例
complex cases you might want to separate
您的客户端和服务器功能
your client and server functions
分成两个独立的模块
into two separate modules
但它实际上很常见并且可以接受
but it's actually quite common and acceptable to have
同一模块中的两种功能
both types of functions in the same module
因为毕竟
because after all
模块只是功能的桶
modules are just buckets for functions
看看我们必须做什么
to see what we would have to do
在客户端和服务端实现一个新的
in the client and the server to implement a new
消息让我们假设我们想要得到
message let's suppose we want to get the
最近认捐总额
total amount of the recent pledges
我们可以做到这一点
we could do that by having
客户得到
the client get the
最近的承诺
recent pledges
然后在客户端进程中汇总它们
and then total them up in the client process
但服务器进程可以做更多
but the server process can do more
而不是简单地存储状态
than simply store state
它实际上可以工作
it can actually do work
这是正确的，只是为了证明这一点
that's right and just to demonstrate that
我们将拥有服务器进程
we'll have the server process
做那个计算
do that computation
所以在底部
so down at the bottom here
我们将再次梳理这段代码
we'll uncombed this code again
因为我们想运行它
because we want to run it
我们将在底部添加一条线
we're going to add a line down at the bottom
我们希望我们的客户端界面看起来像这样
we want our client interface to look like this
p 服务器我们要调用一个函数 total 质押
p server we want to call a function total pledged
那应该返回总数
and that should return the total
然后我们使用检查来检查它
and then we use inspect just to inspect it
所以要让它发挥作用
so to make that work
我们需要定义这个客户端接口函数
we need to define this client interface function
我们将在客户端界面下执行此操作
we'll do that up here under client interface
我只是要复制这个给我们一个良好的开端
I'm just going to copy this one to give us a head start
所以这可以称为总质押
so this can be called total pledged
它将发送到服务器
it's going to send to the server
它需要回复
it needs a reply back
所以它在消息中包含 self
so it includes self in the message
然后
and then the
atom 或此处的消息将被完全承诺
atom or the message here is going to be total pledged
它会模仿函数名
it'll mimic the function name
函数名不一定是真的
that doesn't have to be true that the function name
与消息相同，但这样做很常见
is the same as the message but it's common to do that
然后响应将发回总数
and then the response is going to send back the total
所以这将是总数
so this is going to be the total
我们只是
and we just
提取它并从函数中返回它
extract that and return it from the function
与其他客户端接口功能非常相似
so similar to the other client interface functions
这个函数是同步的
this function is synchronous
它期待来自服务器的回复
it expects a reply from the server
然后我们需要处理消息
then we need to handle the message
在服务器进程中
in the server process
我们需要在这里添加一个爪子
we need to add a claws down here
消息的模式是发件人
the pattern of the message is sender
并且消息是完全承诺的
and the message is total pledged
我们知道我们将不得不发送
and we know we're going to have to send
回寄件人
back to the sender
看起来像这样的消息
a message that looks like this
响应和我们计算的任何总数
response and whatever total we compute
然后我们将不得不重复
and then we're going to have to recurs
以现有状态传递的监听循环
listen loop passing in the existing state
因为我们不会改变状态
because we're not going to change the state
那么服务器要做什么
so what's the work the server is going to do
好吧，我只需要计算这个总数
well I just need to compute this total
现在有几种不同的方法可以做到这一点
now there are a couple different ways to do this
如果你愿意，你可以使用 reduce
you could use reduce if you wanted to
但我要使用地图
but I'm going to use map
所以我要采取我们的状态
so I'm going to take our state
记住我们的状态是一个元组列表
and remember our state is a list of tuples
首先是名字
where the first thing is the name
第二件事
and the second thing
是金额
is the amount
还有一个叫做 lm 的长生不老药的功能
and there's a function that elixir called lm
它需要倾倒
and it takes a topple
我就叫它一秒钟
I'll just call that t for a second
然后它需要你想要得到的索引
and then it takes the index that you want to get
并且有从零开始的索引
and there's zero based index
所以这个会得名
so this one would get the name
这个会得到金额
this one would get the amount
但要与地图一起使用
but to use that with map
我们需要捕获函数
we need to capture the function
所以我们用来捕获操作员
so we used to capture operator
我们想要
and we wanted
把倒塌传给我们，所以这将是
to pass us the topple so this is going to be
与号一
ampersand one
地图将调用此函数
maps going to call this function
列表中的每个元素和
with every element in the list and
每个元素都是一个元组
every element is a tuple
所以我们将元组作为第一个参数传入
so we pass the tuple in as the first argument
然后我们想要金额，所以我们在那里传递一个
and then we want the amount so we pass in one there
所以这会给我们一个清单
so that's going to give us a list of
那么我们可以通过管道输入的所有金额
all the amounts that then we can pipe into e nous
所以这对服务器来说不是很辛苦的工作
so this isn't very hard work for the server to do
但这是工作的一个例子
but it's an example of work
服务器进程现在正在存储状态
the server process is now storing state
并对该状态执行计算
and performing computations on that state
我们把它存起来
we save that away
果然，我们得到一个总数，它是 120
well sure enough we get a total and it's 120
所以我们在接收循环中有几个模式
so we have several patterns in the receive loop
但是如果我们的服务器收到一条消息会发生什么
but what happens if our server receives a message
与这些模式中的任何一个都不匹配
that doesn't match any of these patterns
我们有发送的客户端接口函数
we have client interface functions that send
预期消息
expected messages
但有人可能会向我们发送意想不到的信息
but someone could send us an unexpected message
是的，在底部证明这一点
yeah to demonstrate that down at the bottom here
好吧，我们可以发送到那个坑
well we could just send to that pit
因为开始回坑
because start returns to the pit
我们只会给它发送消息
and we'll just send it the message
哦，这是一个两极
oh it's a two pole
第一个元素停止，第二个是
first element stop and the second one is
锤击时间
hammer time
然后在最后
then at the end
我们将使用 io 并检查进程消息
we'll use io and we'll inspect the processes messages
所以这就是这样的pid消息
so this would be the pid messages just like that
如果我们把它保存起来并运行它
if we save that away and run it
当我们看到最后
while we see at the end
消息包括停止锤子时间
the messages include stop hammer time
所以因为没有
so because none
匹配的模式
of the patterns matched
然后意外的消息只是
then the unexpected message just
作为邮箱在这个过程中徘徊
hangs around in the process as mailbox
所以为了避免像这样弄乱邮箱
so to avoid cluttering the mailbox like this
这最终会影响性能
which can ultimately impact performance
在最后添加一个模式是个好主意
it's a good idea to add a pattern at the end
这将匹配所有消息
that will match all messages
我们在接收到的块中完成
we do that up in the received block
这将是这里的最后一个模式
and it's going to be the last pattern here
我们将使用意想不到的
and we'll just use unexpected
这是一个变量
that's a variable
所以这将匹配任何通过的消息
so that's going to match any message that falls through
然后我们就打印出来
and then we'll just print out
意外消息
unexpected message
然后我们将调用检查该意外消息
and then we'll call inspect on that unexpected message
所以我们基本上只是记录意外消息
so we're basically just logging the unexpected message
然后我们必须记住
and then we have to remember
最后调用监听循环
to call listen loop at the end
所以这可以保证匹配所有意外的消息
so this is guaranteed to match all unexpected messages
因为这是最后的爪子
because it's the last claws
因为我们只是在这里使用变量
and because we just use the variable here
它只会吸收任何消息模式
it's just going to soak up any message pattern
现在如果我们把它保存起来并运行它
now if we save that away and run it
看来我们看到意外消息停止锤子时间
well appear we see unexpected message stop hammer time
但是之后
but then
稍后我们偷看邮箱时
when we peek in the mailbox a little bit later on
没有消息
there are no messages
所以这里有一些重要的事情要记住
so here's something important to keep in mind
想象一下我们的网络服务器有五个
imagine our web server gets five
创建质押的并发请求
concurrent requests to create a pledge
这导致五个创建
this results in five create
承诺信息
pledge messages
被发送到我们的单一质押服务器进程
being sent to our single pledge server process
记得虽然收到
remember though that receive
总是一次处理一条消息
always handles messages one at a time
所以虽然每个请求
so although each request
同时运行并且可能并行运行
runs concurrently and likely in parallel
消息处理是
message handling is
始终在服务器进程中进行消毒，并且
always sterilized in the server process and
因为这样的服务器进程是
as such server processes are
应用程序中的同步点
synchronization points in an application
现在最初这似乎不是最佳的
now initially this might seem sub optimal
但这正是
but it's exactly how
我们希望管理服务器状态
we want the server state to be managed
你能想象有多个并发进程吗
can you imagine having multiple concurrent processes
所有人都试图在同一时间更新现金
all trying to update the cash at exactly the same time
这对所有人都是免费的
it would be a free for all
现金很可能会腐败
and the cash would likely become corrupted
所以虽然看起来服务器
so while it appears that the server
过程只是存储状态
process is simply storing state
它实际上做的不止这些
it's actually doing more than that
通过消毒访问
by sterilizing access
它正在维护该州的完整性
it's preserving the integrity of that state
同时来自多个并发进程的负载不足
while underload from multiple concurrent processes
所以现在我们知道如何存储一个简单的状态
so now we know how to store a simple state
在一个服务器进程中，可以
in a server process that can
也做其他工作
also do other work
在下一节
in the next section
我们将看看如何使服务器代码更通用
we'll look at how to make the server code more generic
我们正在前往 gen 服务器的路上
and we're on our way to a gen server